practitioners
ladies and gentlemen it is a pleasure to
welcome you all to the seventh edition
of the icici lumbar general insurance
and cnbc tv 18 present india risk
management awards over the last six
years these awards have become the most
coveted platform to recognize and
celebrate the best risk management teams
and initiatives which are innovative
path defining and yet grounded in a
strong base of risk management
fundamentals as we hold the first ever
virtual edition of this prestigious
award show in the backdrop of the
ongoing pandemic there is no escaping
the fact that kovit 19 has demonstrated
that risk is not a well-behaved house
guest predicting the unpredictable
dealing with risk and uncertainty it has
always been a key mantra in the risk
management industry and this holds true
today as well as we all continue to
recover from the impact of covet 19. the
focus is on enhancing the resilience of
our economies and societies this evening
we recognize and celebrate
the risk managers of tomorrow who have
shown
great foresight and a dynamic approach
to upgrade and reposition risk
management in their organizations this
year and now to set the ball rolling i'd
like to invite cnbc tv 18's executive
editor lata venkatesh to deliver the
welcome address over to you
thank you very much gotham uh first up
dr ram charan the management guru
bhargav dasgupta
lombard jurors award winners and the
creme de la creme of india's legal and
financial mind space on behalf of cnbc
tv 18 on on my own behalf and our
co-sponsors i say lombard i once again
welcome all of you to the seventh
edition of the india risk management
awards cnbc tv 18 actually partners with
many entities to recognize excellence in
various areas so we have business awards
through the year but the risk management
award is by far the most demanding most
thoroughly analyzing and hence a
personal favorite for me
the winners today have been picked after
a very trying and thorough process
and
uh that we have been able to get all of
you award winners on one platform makes
this day very special thank you very
much and many congratulations just this
one sir to be able to see all and
congratulate you all i was hoping that
this would be
an on-site uh event and not a virtual
event but nevertheless i'm looking
forward to enjoying this evening thank
you very much
and thank you for that love and that
sets the tone of the evening in fact and
now i would like to invite the man who
has staunchly supported these awards for
all of its six editions bhargav dasgupta
managing director and ceo icici lombard
general insurance uh to deliver the
keynote address over to you sir
uh thank you and uh and a warm welcome
to all of you from um you know from ics
lombard and from me personally to the
seventh edition of india risk management
awards
now in the previous episodes of this
platform we have been uh deliberating
the role and the importance of risk
management
and how india incorporated needs to
adapt to it realistically and over the
years we've always had this big debate
about you know what should we focus on
is it risk or is it you know growth
and is it complementary is it uh you
know is it uh at uh odds with each other
i think the experience that in the world
has gone through in the last uh you know
10 months unfortunately has taught us
that risk management is core to survival
and in a extremely volatile and
uncertain world that we live in
it is
a foundation for success it's not
something that you do also it's
something that you build your you know
strategy on a foundation of
now at isis in humber uh our approach
has been uh
moving away from just being a risk
transfer partner which is what
traditional insurers do but to be a more
of a holistic risk management partner so
we work with corporates to actually
analyze risk and
partner with them to reduce this risk
and as a course of that discussion when
we continuously engage with corporate
firms to understand their needs
and accordingly empower them with
relevant risk management solutions we
saw one gap that was clearly emerging
diverse organizations across
size scale you know the industry
they grapple with challenges where you
know such as difficulty in
quantifying the risk that they're
exposed to as also benchmarking and
effectively gauging
where they are in terms of risk
preparedness in comparison with with the
others so given this deliberation one of
the things that we uh you know one of
the insights that we got uh you know
helped us in crafting something that we
believe is truly first of its kind one
of its kind in india uh based on our
discussion with some of you uh you know
including some of the experts we believe
that even across the world uh an index
like this that we are about to launch
today doesn't exist so you know i'm
personally very happy to announce the
launch of this index we call it icc
lombard corporate india risk index
it's an index which uh is unified it's
comprehensive it's uh quantifiable uh it
measures
uh risks across 32 different parameters
it buckets these into then two specific
areas again providing quantitative
scores for each one for the level of
risk that a firm is exposed to and
second the extent to which the
organization is prepared in case the
risks were to strike so in a sense we
are you know giving them a uh giving the
organization corporates a clear tool to
establish and understand where they are
in terms of the risk and where they
stand in terms of preparedness to
address the risk uh you know at the end
let me uh
congratulate uh all the winners of this
event uh you know we'll continue this
tradition of uh celebrating india's best
best risk managers we see lots of awards
in you know many other areas but risk
management something that we felt in the
past was
relatively under appreciated and under
awarded and that's what we are trying to
change thank you once again for joining
us today and wish you a great evening
ahead
thank you
well uh we have a special av lined up on
the on the corporate risk index the
icici
general insurance risk index so let's
take a quick look at that uh for all of
your benefit
[Music]
all right i'd like to invite global
president and managing partner of the
frost and sullivan
arub sutri to throw more light on the
just on icici lombard corporate india
risk index over to you if you
talk to people in the industry
it is very clear that many of the people
are still struggling with this do not
fully understand what it means and
despite having been educated a lot still
do not have a full comprehensive
understanding of how risk
factors have to be understood and how do
you manage risk in the in in the
business and so when we talk to
all the cxos as well as the risk
officers in the business one thing that
we find is that most of them have very
different definitions of risk whether it
is scale measurement techniques it is
very very different and that's one of
the reasons why oftentimes people simply
don't put all of these things together
so there is no skill that exists today
that is standardized across sectors and
cannot be considered unified at all and
that's where
we spend a lot of time working together
and building
a very comprehensive index
so if you look at
how the risk frameworks work today the
typical risk models measure probability
and impact but we have taken a
completely different approach where we
measure the firm's exposure and its
ability to manage risk and which is a
lot more relevant in today's context for
business continuity and more importantly
top line and evident margin growth so
risk index as you can see is a measure
of how well you are being able to manage
the risks you are exposed to
but more importantly how do you
navigate that fine line between risk
being an opportunity or a threat to your
business and that's why this balance
makes it very very important
so what we've done is actually
looked at
you know
leveraging our standard methodology we
looked at well-established advisory best
practices and we have combined it with
the principle of lean and six sigma to
create a comprehensive risk matrix that
covers all aspects of the indian
corporate risk exposure and we've
covered it around 15 sectors ranging
from new age industries to
multinationals to mncs and of course
medium and small enterprises as well and
obviously this is just the start we
expect that this will continue and will
build on what we have put together and
so based on that we have come up with
the ic ic lombard corporate india risk
index and so the the point here is
it is a it is a very different scale and
it does not say that higher is better or
lower is better so for example if you
have a score of 50 to 60 it tells you
that you know your risk very well and
that you are being able to adjust and
manage these risks better
likewise a score of 60 to 80 tells you
that you have done some smart moves you
made some smart decisions and you've
prepared yourself for the future and so
based on that
what we've done is come up with the
corporate india risk index obviously
it's a very superior risk index and
industries like the healthcare bfsi
media telecom and it and its typically
form the part of this
high risk index in the country and they
of course have high exposure but they've
also done very well in risk management
but the real economy sectors like the
metals or more manufacturing
uh have have managed the risk
really well overall but not to the level
that we would expect and the new age
hospitality and logistics sectors have
had high intrinsic risk exposure which
are being to some extent
handled suboptimally
indeed thank you so much uh mr zucchi
and as they say let there be light
but before we continue may i request
that we play the special video on the
icici lombard
well it's time now for a special segment
and for that it's over to you lata well
thank you very much uh gotham
to all of you uh if you remember in the
past in the previous awards we have
normally invited
economists you know kenneth rogoff
reinhardt
merely because we thought that there are
risks in the economy but corvette
changed our thinking
for covet-affected companies we thought
one thing the doctor would order is a
management guru like dr ramcharan
you know dr charan is known for many
things but the most important attribute
is his ability to give ceos and boards
practical real-world actionable
solutions the kind of advice you can
actually use
monday morning dr taran i welcome you to
deliver your special address i assure
you this is the moment we have been
waiting for all your sir
thank you very much
i'm humbled
my mission in life
is to write to talk to deliver
hopefully useful to the practitioners
i will be brief i will try to the point
i congratulate the icici lombard
and the ceo arup from foster sullivan
to create this corporate risk
index
it's timely
it's innovative
and it is indispensable
on the boards i serve seven of them
across the globe
risk is now at the board level
the second largest
funds largest is
the the the one
blackrock second is the vanguard
the chairman of vanguard is just
finishing up his research and a book
it's called tsr
talent
strategy and risk
if these three are integrated
if these three inputs are correct
against the environment and competition
you will have tsr
total shareholder
return
this will come out sometime in october
and as i mentioned this
the intent of this
index
as
bhagavad-gita put it
and i totally agree
to improve performance
no strategies without risk no business
without no business model without risk
so it's at the center of choice of
strategy
choice of business model
choice of resource allocation
so our job as risk people
is to have this at the center
in the decisions that the board makes
the ceo and the exot makes
in resource allocations in behaviors
if you are looking at esg
it is going to be affecting behaviors at
the plant level
if you're looking at cyber
it's going to the behaviors
of the people using all that
the the data
and how they use the devices
this balance is a central part it's
innovative it's new
and just put these things together now
the thing i want to mention
that it is not defensive
many people take risk
as a defensive
risk as i think the the ceo president
sullivan put it it's also an opportunity
and that is we can now quantify
the return on risk
it comes this way it's well known in the
financial side
if your risk balance and opportunity and
exposure is right
and it is balanced with your profit
opportunity over time
it will have an impact on your sector
what funds are coming what firms are not
coming
it will an effect on your company within
the sector
that will affect the price earning ratio
so the market value change
is the return
so
the key thing to watch
is that
our own people
need to demonstrate that we can earn
costs of capital
the more we can demonstrate cost of
capital
the more confidence we build
of course it has to have risk premium
more fdi will come
china's is a 250 billion a year for a
long time
we too can do it
but the first part is execution
second
the government has to pose attention
that we have accountability
and earning cost of capital
we have not done so in telecom
we have not done so in power plant
we have not done so airlines
and so when i sit on the other side of
the table
where the funds are coming
the question is the country risk
now that country risk
and the sectors are not able to run cost
of capital
that's coming in
by the indians
because our indian ceos are very good
we have in largest companies in the
world run by indian ceos they're
algorithmic ones i am interacting now
with 100 million dollar companies in
india
200 million dollar companies these are
superb entrepreneurs they're superb
business people they need help in
scaling up so we need to have this in
mind
and our
future is very bright thank you
ics hair lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards honoring
the new age risk